one way to picture the number n cubed is
to lay down n copies of an N by n Square
side by side flat if we use this
representation here we get a diagram
that represents the sum of the first n
cubes in this case we've shown n equals
four no matter what cubic stack we start
with we can now take four copies and
strategically shift and rotate them as
shown if we do that right we fill in a
perfect square with side length N
squared plus n therefore four copies of
the sum of the first n cubes must be
equal to the square of N squared plus n
this means that the sum of the first n
cubes must be equal to the quantity N
squared plus N squared divided by four